Cindy Kei

New York, NY 11375 | 347-423-9074 | myk245@nyu.edu Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio Website

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Fullstack Software Engineer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript based programming. During my time in Publishing, I utilized my strong organizational, analytical thinking, and collaboration skills to drive sales in international and domestic book rights. My goal is to join a forward-thinking company and to take part in the vast power inherent to the realm of Software Engineering to create intelligent solutions for social change.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, PostgreSQL, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Heroku

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Virago - Github | Demo

A centralized resource and community support system for those affected by mental health disorders

- Utilized PostgreSQL and Active Record to create and maintain a database of mental health disorders and associated models
- Employed Bootstrap and custom CSS to design a user-friendly application
- Incorporated a tag system that allows users to search through blog posts by disorders

Fashion App - Github

An innovative fashion app that allows users to curate and browse outfits

- Utilized React and Rails to create a virtual closet that allows users to add products to their collection
- Made use of Bootstrap and media to enable users to visualize how an outfit would look like on a human model

The Cellar - Github

An ecommerce app for wine lovers

- Used a JavaScript frontend with Rails backend to allow users to explore wine options by type and note
- Built a review feature allowing users to leave their opinions and thoughts on particular wines

WORK EXPERIENCE

Simon & SchusterNew York, NYSubsidiary Rights Associate04/2017 - 12/2019

- Compiled sales reports and presentation materials to drive foreign sales
- Crafted and pitched serial excerpts to targeted publications; contributed \$12,000/year in serial sales

The Aldan Troy Group

New York, NY

Merchandising Assistant, Bergdorf Goodman

10/2016 - 04/2017

- Coordinated merchandise allocation and maintained price changes in database
- Coded purchase orders into merchandising system and compiled weekly sales reports

Oxford University Press

New York, NY

Editorial Intern

10/2015 - 05/2016

- Edited manuscript drafts and prepared manuscripts for handover to production
- Assisted with preparation of budgets and proposals

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

01/2020 - 05/2020

New York University

New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts, Linguistic Anthropology Minor in Communicative Sciences and Disorders

3.9 GPA, Summa Cum Laude, Phi Beta Kappa

08/2010 - 05/2014